JavaScript must be turned on to use this page.

Menu[](https://lernu.net/)

Privacy Policy
==============

Controller
----------

The controller responsible for the processing of data on this website is:

Studio GAUS GmbH  
Erich-Steinfurth-Str. 6  
10243 Berlin  
Germany

* Internet: [https://studiogaus.com](https://studiogaus.com/)
* Email: [info@studiogaus.com](mailto:info@studiogaus.com)

The contact details we publish in the context of our obligation to provide a legal notice for our website may not be used by third parties to send us information and advertisements, unless we have expressly requested such information and advertisements to be sent. We reserve the right to take legal measures should we receive unsolicited promotional information (e.g. spam emails).

Since pursuant to [Article 37](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e3732-1-1) of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) we are under no obligation to designate a company data-protection officer, we do not have a specific person responsible for data protection whose contact details we could publish here. But even though we do not have a designated company data-protection officer, we still fulfil all our obligations in the context of data processing with the required professional care.

Collection and storage of personal data
---------------------------------------

### General information on data processing

We would like to inform you below about the way we collect personal data if you use our website. “Personal data” include all data that relate to you as a person, e.g. your name, address, email addresses, user behaviour, etc.

In addition to the option of using our Services simply to obtain information, we also offer a range of other services that you may use, should you be interested. In this case, you will generally have to provide further personal data which we will use to provide the relevant service; the data-processing policy which we have set out above will also apply to this type of personal data.

We will sometimes commission external service providers to process your data. We select and commission our service providers with due care; they are subject to our direction, and are regularly monitored. You will find detailed information below on the operations necessary in cases where we commission service providers to provide certain functions for our Online Services, or where we wish to use your data for advertising purposes. In this connection, we will also inform you about the criteria we will apply to the period for which the personal data will be stored.

We may furthermore disclose your personal data to third parties in cases where we join forces with partners to give our users a chance to use certain services, such as participating in special activities, going in for competitions to win prizes, or concluding a contract. More detailed information on this issue is provided below in the context of a description of each particular service.

The data will be erased as soon as they are no longer needed for the purpose for which they were collected.

### Purpose of processing

Storing and processing of such data is necessary for the proper functioning of the Online Services, e.g. in order to provide the Online Services to users, or to enable users to contact us. We use the data to improve the functioning of our Online Services and in order to ensure that our information technology systems are secure.

### Contacting us

If you contact us via email or using the contact form, your data (name as well as contact details, if provided) and your message will be processed solely for the purpose of processing and handling your enquiry. In compliance with [Article 6(1)(b) GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e1888-1-1) or [Article 6(1)(f) GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e1888-1-1), as the case may be, we will process this type of data for the purpose of handling your enquiry. As soon as your enquiry has been fully processed, your data will be erased. Your data will be erased if circumstances show that the matter in question has been conclusively settled, and no statutory data retention obligations stand in the way of us erasing the data.

### Data processing if you visit our website

We will only log the personal data that your browser transmits to our server if you use our website solely to obtain information, i.e. if you do not register or transmit information to us in any other manner. If you view our website, we will collect the type of data described below. We require these data for technical reasons, in order to be able to display our website to you and also to guarantee its stability and security. The legal basis for data processing is provided by [Article 6(1)(f) GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e1888-1-1).

The following data will be collected in this context: your IP address (anonymised), the date and time of the request, the time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT), the subject matter of the request (the specific web page accessed), the access status and/or the HTTP status code, the volume of data transmitted in each case, the website from which the request was transmitted, your browser, your operating system and its desktop, and the language and version of your browser software.

In the event that the data are stored in log files, the data will be erased no later than seven days after they were stored. The data may also be stored for a longer period. Should they be stored for a longer period, any user’s IP address will be erased or distorted; it will therefore no longer be possible to correlate the accessing client with the data.

### Cookies

Cookies are small files that the website that is accessed places on a user’s computer with the aid of the web browser; the aim of a cookie, at a later stage, is to provide the server with the information on the user that the cookie has stored. The present website uses the two types of cookies described below; their scope and method of operation are also explained below:

* Temporary cookies will be erased automatically as soon as you close your browser. This type of cookie particularly includes so-called session cookies. Session cookies store a so-called “session ID” that enables a cookie to assign the various requests from your browser to the joint session shared by all these requests. This will enable our server to recognise your computer when you return to our website. Session cookies will be erased as soon as you log out or close your browser.
* Permanent cookies are erased automatically after a predetermined period has elapsed; this period may vary, depending on the type of cookie. You can erase cookies in the security settings of your browser at any time.

You can also configure your browser settings to reflect your wishes; you can refuse, for instance, to accept third party cookies, or any cookies at all. Please note that in that case you may not be able to use certain functions of the present website.

### Creating and using a customer account

Even if you do not log in to our website, you will still have no difficulty in using a number of our services. However, if you wish to use the full range of functions our website offers, you will have to create your own personal user account. If you register with our website, certain personal data will always be collected, e.g. your name, email address and password. In order to protect ourselves from misuse and other unauthorised use, we will also store the last IP address used, the language you selected, the date of registration, and the date on which the registered person last logged in.

During registration you can choose whether you want to be identified by a user name of your choice, or by your real name. Only your user name will always be visible to all other registered persons.

If required, you may at any time modify or erase the data you provided during registration; please use the following link for this purpose: [https://lernu.net/uzanto/agordoj](https://lernu.net/uzanto/agordoj).

Finally, we also collect and store data on the progress a registered user has made in learning a language; this may include information about the lessons he or she has already completed, the words learnt, or the tests he or she has done. The purpose of this type of data collection is to support and help registered persons while they are learning, and also to continually improve and optimise, for the benefit of all users, the services provided on our website. Some of these data may be visible to other registered persons, e.g. in the form of “points scored”. This type of personal data is directly linked to a specific customer account; the data are anonymised as soon as the purpose of data processing ceases to exist.

In compliance with [Article 6(1)(a) GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e1888-1-1), the basis for processing your data is the consent you gave when you registered your user account. The legal basis for processing the other types of personal data mentioned above is [Article 6(1)(f) GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e1888-1-1).

### Online presence on social media

We maintain an online presence on social networks and platforms in order to be able to communicate with any person, user and interested party active on these networks and platforms, and in order to provide them with information about our own activities. If you access any of these networks or platforms, the business terms and data-processing policies of the relevant provider will apply.

Unless provided for otherwise in our Privacy Policy, we will process the data of data subjects (persons concerned) who communicate with us via social networks or platforms, e.g. in the event that data subjects post on our online presence or send us a message.

### Google AdSense

The present website uses the online advertising service Google AdSense, which is used to present you with advertising geared to your interests. In so doing, we aim to show you advertising that might be of interest to you, thereby making our website more interesting to you. In order to do so, we collect statistical information about you, which is then further processed by our advertising partners. Such advertisements can be identified by the “Google ad” caption displayed in an advertisement.

If you visit our website, Google will be notified that you have accessed our website. Google uses a web beacon for this purpose, which will set a cookie on your computer. The data specified in Clause 2 of this Privacy Policy will be transmitted in the context of Google AdSense. We have no control over the data collected. We also do not possess any information on the scope of the data collected or on the period for which they will be stored. Your data will be transmitted to the United States, and will be analysed there. If you are logged in to your Google account, your data may be assigned to your specific account. If you do not wish your data to be assigned to your Google profile, you will need to log out. Data may possibly be disclosed to Google’s contractual partners, to third parties or to public authorities.

The legal basis for the processing of your data is provided by [Article 6(1)(f) GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e1888-1-1).

The present website does not place any third-party advertisement via Google AdSense.

You have various options of preventing Google AdSense cookies from being installed:

* you can use a setting in your browser software that prevents such cookies; you will, for example, not receive any third-party advertisements if you set your browser to reject third-party cookies;
* you can go to Google and disable the provision of interest-based advertisements via the following link: [http://www.google.de/ads/preferences](http://www.google.de/ads/preferences), with the proviso that this setting will be deleted if you delete your cookies;
* you can disable the provision of interest-based advertisements from service providers that are part of the self-regulatory initiatives “About Ads” and “Your Online Choices” by clicking on the following link: [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices), with the proviso that this setting will be deleted if you delete your cookies;
* you can prevent such cookies from being installed, by permanently disabling this option in your Firefox browser, Internet Explorer browser or Google Chrome browser via the following link: [http://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin](http://www.google.com/settings/ads/plugin). Please note that in that case you may not be able to use certain functions of the present Online Services to their full extent.

You can request further information on the purpose and scope of data collection and processing, and on the rights and setting options you can use to protect your privacy, from: 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountainview, California 94043, USA; advertising privacy policy: [https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads). Google has opted in to the EU-US Privacy Shield: [https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework).

### Google Analytics

The present website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (hereinafter called “Google”). Google Analytics uses so-called “cookies”, i.e. text files that are stored on your computer, which enable your use of the present website to be analysed. The information a cookie generates about your use of the website will generally be transmitted to a Google server in the United States and stored there. If IP anonymisation is enabled on the present website, any of your IP addresses originating within a Member State of the European Union or another Contracting Party to the Agreement on the European Economic Area will be truncated by Google before transmission. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google Server in the United States and truncated there. Google will use such information on behalf of the operator of the present website to analyse the way you use the website, to compile reports on website activities, and to perform further services for the website operator in respect of usage of the website and the internet.

The IP address transmitted by your browser in connection with Google Analytics will not be merged with other data held by Google.

You can prevent the cookies from being stored, by activating a setting in your browser software to prevent this; however, please note that in that case you may not be able to use certain functions of the present website to their full extent. You can furthermore prevent Google from collecting and processing such data (including your IP address) that are generated by cookies and refer to your use of the website, by downloading and installing the browser plug-in that is retrievable via the following link: [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

The present website uses Google Analytics with the “\_anonymizeIp()” function. With the help of this function, IP addresses are processed in truncated form so as to rule out IP addresses being traced to a specific person. To the extent that the data collected on you refer to you personally, any such reference is thereby immediately prevented; as a consequence, personal data are immediately erased.

We use Google Analytics to analyse and continually improve use of our website. The statistics generated help us to improve our Online Services, thereby providing you with a more interesting user experience. Google has opted in to the EU-US Privacy Shield with regard to any exceptional cases in which personal data are transmitted to the United States: [https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework](https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework).

The legal basis for the use of Google Analytics is provided by [Article 6(1)(f) GDPR](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679#d1e1888-1-1).

Any personal data will be erased or anonymised no more than 14 months after they were collected.

Third-party service provider information: Google Dublin, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland; terms of use: [https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/terms/us/](https://marketingplatform.google.com/about/analytics/terms/us/), summary of data protection measures: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/learn/privacy.html](http://www.google.com/intl/en/analytics/learn/privacy.html), and privacy policy: [http://www.google.de/intl/en/policies/privacy](http://www.google.de/intl/en/policies/privacy).

You will find more information on data protection at: [https://policies.google.com/privacy](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

Period for which the data will be stored
----------------------------------------

We adhere to the principles of data reduction and data economy. We will store personal data for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which the personal data are processed; we will also cease storing your personal data as soon as you withdraw your previously given consent. As soon as the particular purpose ceases to apply and/or whenever you exercise any of the relevant rights you have as a data subject, the data in question will be made unavailable, anonymised and/or erased in accordance with the rules and statutory provisions.

Any person who has registered will be able to delete their account here at any time: [https://lernu.net/uzanto/agordoj](https://lernu.net/uzanto/agordoj).

Rights of a data subject (person concerned)
-------------------------------------------

### Exercising your rights

Should you no longer agree to your personal data being stored, or should your personal data have become incorrect, upon being instructed by you to do so, we will arrange for your data to be erased or made unavailable, or we will carry out the necessary corrections, as the case may be (and insofar as this is possible under applicable law). The same applies if you require us to make only restricted use of certain data in future.

Please contact us by the following means if you have any questions about the processing of your personal data or wish to be provided with information or wish to have data corrected, made unavailable, erased or transmitted to another company, or object to the use of data:

Studio GAUS GmbH, Erich-Steinfurth-Str. 6, 10243 Berlin, countries

* Internet: [https://studiogaus.com](https://studiogaus.com/)
* Email: [info@studiogaus.com](mailto:info@studiogaus.com)

If you exercise your right to objection, please state your grounds for objecting to your personal data being processed in the manner in which we have previously processed them. If you lodge a justified objection, we will first check the factual circumstances. We will then either cease to process your data or adjust processing or, alternatively, inform you about the compelling grounds warranting particular protection, according to which we will continue to process your data.

If you have consented to the processing of your data, you may withdraw this consent at any time with effect for the future. Once you have notified us of such a withdrawal, the withdrawal will affect the admissibility of processing your personal data.

Last updated: December 15, 2019

English

© 2002-2024 lernu.net | [Impressum](https://lernu.net/impressum)

×

#### Choose your language

Help us translate the site! [More information](https://lernu.net/kunlaboro)

×

...
